Welcome to the new feature introduction video of Marvelous Designer 2025.
In this video, we will introduce a new keyframe animation function for you.
Now you can perform keyframe animation settings on multiple objects to complete various animation effects.
In the new version, a new animation button has been added.
Click on this button, and you can see a variety of elements in the drop-down menu.
You can perform keyframes for plants, panels, virtual models, fixed needles, wind controllers, and simulation attributes.
In order to demonstrate how to use this function, I have prepared a virtual model with walking movements.
You can go to the drawing window, find the virtual model, male model, walking show movement,
and then click on the Connect property table.
Download the catwalkinplace action file and apply it to the virtual model.
Now let's learn how to use these keyframe animations.
First is the keyframe animation of the plant.
In the drop-down menu, select Increase Plant Animation.
Then select a fabric type that you apply for clothing.
Click on the small arrow on the left side of the plant name.
There are two options for front material or physical properties.
Here I will demonstrate how to modify the front material of the fabric through the keyframe.
In the property editor, the property options with the keyframe button on the right side can be opened.
I will demonstrate how to change the color of the clothing every 30 frames.
First, go back to the starting frame and add the keyframe of the color.
Then set the current frame to 30 frames, then change the color and add the keyframe.
For the modification of the single property, the manual keyframe may be a bit complicated.
At this time, you can turn on the automatic keyframe function.
After that, when you change the property, you will automatically add a keyframe under the current frame.
It is more convenient to add a keyframe.
Drag the right end of the animation bar of the entire plant and drag it to the end of the animation position.
As the keyframe animation bar is released, you can see that the mark where the keyframe is located has also been moved.
Now play the animation, you will see the color of the vest change.
Next, let's take a look at the keyframe animation of the board.
In the animation menu, select the board.
There are many board names that can be selected in this menu.
To determine the name of the board to be modified, you can select the board in the 3D window.
Then go to the property editor, modify its name, and you can find it in the menu.
Since the following will use the keyframe animation to adjust the cool leg effect, I modified the name of the four cool leg boards.
After the modification is complete, go back to the animation menu.
In this menu, find the four boards made up of cool leg boards and add an animation layer for each of them.
Click on the small arrow on the left side of the animation layer name to play the download menu.
You can open it here and see the keyframe layer of the board.
Here we can open the fabric used for the board.
First, record the fabric used at the beginning.
Then drag the play button to the back of the number of frames and add a new fabric from the store.
Then open the automatic keyframe and switch the fabrics of these boards to the animation layer of the keyframe of the board.
Since the automatic keyframe is turned on, every time the fabric is changed, it will automatically record the keyframe of the board.
When modifying the keyframe in the number of frames, you can select multiple keyframes in the frame and move them at the same time.
After the adjustment is complete, let's look at the final effect.
Next, let's take a look at the keyframe animation of the fixed frame.
There are two uses of fixed frames.
The first is to use the fixed frame.
The second is to use the fixed frame to fix the clothing or fabric on the static object and then record the animation.
The third is to use the fixed frame to fix the grid of the clothing to the virtual model with the animation, and then move or separate them together.
First, let's take a look at the static use scene.
Here we will use the fixed frame to fix part of the towel on the clip to blow the wind.
In the fixed frame part, we will add the fixed frame to the position of the clip near the clip.
Press the W key to click the board and you can add the fixed frame to the board.
Since the closet is introduced in the form of a virtual model, we can fix the fixed frame on the towel to the closet.
The fixed frame will automatically be fixed to the grid of the virtual model closest to it.
Please note that the fixed frame is located on the top of the grid.
The fixed frame will calculate the conflict thickness and surface stiffness when fixed to the grid.
For a more realistic simulation effect, please reduce the conflict thickness of the towel and the surface stiffness of the clothing.
Open the simulation again, you can see that the effect of re-calculating the effect of conflict thickness and surface stiffness is more realistic.
Next, let's try to make the effect of towel drop by using the fixed frame key to make the towel drop.
Similar to the previous animation, in the downline menu,
find the fixed frame option and then adjust these fixed frames by using the name.
To make it easier to handle, please modify the name of these fixed frames in the attribute editor.
After modifying the name, increase the animation layer for these fixed frames one by one.
Next, let's use the fixed frame animation to make the effect of towel drop by one side.
To make the wind blowing effect more natural, we set a initial state for the wind controller to be closed.
Next, open the animation again.
At the beginning, record the state of the unactivated, then open it at the time of activation.
The activation of the wind controller records the key frame.
Next, at the beginning of the animation, record the activation state of the fixed frame.
Then, at the appropriate position, record the activation state of the fixed frame.
According to the position of the wind controller, first cancel the activation of the two fixed frames on the left side,
then cancel the activation of the two fixed frames on the right side.
Then, turn on the recording.
You can see that there are continuous activation states of the fixed frame, so the towel has also dropped.
Next, let's see how to make a bill with the hand moving and then falling animation.
First, increase the fixed frame on the board, then fix the fixed frame to the virtual model,
so that it moves with the virtual model's hand.
Open the simulation, check if the fixed frame is correct, fix the board to the model's hand,
then turn on the recording, check the effect of the bill board with the hand moving.
After confirming the effect,
we can start setting the key frame for the fixed frame.
First, add a fixed frame animation layer.
Refer to the character action in the 3D window at the appropriate position,
record the activation of the fixed frame and the activation of the anti-activation key frame.
In order to check the animation effect of the fixed frame cancellation,
we can set the playback area to be smaller first,
and record a short animation.
After setting the playback area, start recording the animation.
If the recording effect is not very natural,
we can start recording from a little further ahead,
so that the animation recording time is longer,
then check the effect.
If in the process of re-recording,
there is a problem with the fixed frame error,
you can try to remove the fixed frame,
and re-attach it to the virtual model again.
After adjustment, open the recording again to check the effect.
Now you can see that the billboard moves with the hand first,
and then the effect falls off the hand.
Since we just used the wind controller,
now let's learn about the key animation of the wind controller.
First, in the animation download menu,
select the wind controller,
add the animation bar of the wind controller,
then go to the 3D window,
open the display wind controller.
At this time, close the infinite border of the wind controller,
the wind controller will return to the type of display wind range.
For reference,
refer to the direction of the wind,
then select the wind controller,
click the shrink icon in the upper right corner,
change the position of the ball to the shrink position of the ball,
drag the three-color axis to adjust the size of the wind controller,
and thus affect its wind range.
We can use the key needle to
K the position and the rotation angle of the wind controller.
You can adjust the position of the wind controller by the position of the position,
the rotation angle,
or by dragging the key needle to the bottom of the menu.
When we click the key needle icon on the right side of the variable option,
all key needles in the chess menu,
such as positioning and rotation,
will be added to the corresponding key needle.
We put the position of the wind controller in the clockwise direction,
around the virtual model and put it in a circle.
Here we copy and paste the key needle,
so that the position of the wind controller
between the two completely identical key needles
will not change.
It looks like it has stopped here for a while.
Then you can refer to the position of the wind controller in the 3D window,
adjust the key needle.
Key needles also have different types of settings.
Under default, the option is linear change,
which means that the value between the two key needles is linear change.
If you choose to keep the value,
then from the position of the key needle,
the data will remain in the next key needle position.
The three-time function is a three-time function change.
At the beginning, the change is smaller.
When approaching the last key needle,
the number of changes is greater.
Now let's open the infinite border option,
so that all the materials in the scene are affected by the wind force.
Then, by setting the key needle,
the wind force is gradually increased.
Start recording to see the final effect.
Finally, let's take a look at the key needle animation of the simulation attribute.
When you create the animation layer of the simulation attribute,
you will see a hint.
The hint is that the key needle of your simulation attribute
can only be used when the simulation type is self-defined.
Therefore, we will first modify the simulation quality to user self-defined.
Now the animation layer of the simulation attribute will be activated.
Here you can set the key needle animation as two attributes.
One is gravity and the other is air resistance.
The gravity is adjusted to the size of the gravity field in the 3D window.
The negative of the force affects the direction of the force field.
Increased resistance will increase the air resistance,
making the fabric slower to move.
First, we return these values to the default value,
and then set the key needle in the starting position.
Then raise the air resistance to 500,
and adjust the gravity to 9800.
Move the front needle to the position you think is appropriate,
and then set the key needle.
To make the transition more natural,
now please modify the transition type of the key needle to 3D.
Then click the record button to see the final recording animation.